Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Borbetomagus, May-December 2017; cuid5860; Borbetomagus (Musical group); 7 websites in 1 archived website
  Borbetomagus is a musical group composed of Jim Sauter on saxophone, Don Dietrich on saxophone, Donald Miller on guitar, and Adam Nodelman on bass. The group was formed in 1979 and specializes in free improvisation and noise music. The band has released numerous albums since 1980, some of which include At In Roads, Industrial Strengths, Asbestos Shake, Buncha Hair That Long, and Experience the Magic.
- Botelho, Paul J., April 2014- ongoing; cuid5861; Botelho, Paulo Jorge, 1974-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of pauljbotelho.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; list of his works; including musical compositions, visual art, and software that he has designed; and a calendar of his events.
  Paul J. Botelho is an Azorean-American composer and vocalist. His compositions include acoustic and electro-acoustic music; multimedia installation pieces; visual artworks; vocal improvisations; and one-act operas. As a vocalist, he is a countertenor. Some of his vocal pieces include In Moscow We Marched (2019-2020), Visby Project (2017-2018), and Walmart 3 AM (2016).
- Botti, Susan, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of susanbotti.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped to capture YouTube videos.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of Botti; news about the artist; event listings; a catalog of work with embedded audio and video files; three photo galleries; a media section that includes her discography and print publications; and her contact information. The crawl also includes the website for her duo, Duo della Luna.
  Susan Botti (b. 1962) is a soprano singer and composer of music featuring classical and improvisational styles for both vocal and instrumental performance. Her repertoire includes chamber, orchestral, large ensemble, wind ensemble, and theatrical pieces. She is often the vocal soloist of her own compositions. Botti is also part of the Duo della Luna, a vocal and violin duo formed with Airi Yoshioka that specializes in contemporary music and folk-inspired arrangements and compositions.
- Boyce, Douglas, February 2015-ongoing; cuid5855; Boyce, Douglas, 1970-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of douglasboyce.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains information about Boyce's albums and projects; updates; embedded video files; a biography of the artist; press quotes; an artist statement; and links to podcasts and interviews featuring the artist. The website also contains an announcement of his recently released work with counter)induction.
  Douglas Boyce (b. 1970) is a composer who specializes in chamber music that draws on Medieval Renaissance and modernist themes. Boyce's works are aesthetically and technically centered around humanistic traditions. He is also a composer-in-residence of the counter)induction music ensemble, for which he created his most recent work titled Dit de l'alerion. Previous album releases by Boyce include The Bird is an Alphabet, The Hunt by Night, and Some Consequences.
- Boyer, Peter, February 2015-ongoing; Boyer, Peter, 1970-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of propulsivemusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Peter Boyer (b. 1970) is a Grammy-nominated composer, orchestrator, and conductor for orchestras, films, and television. One of Boyer's most notable works is Ellis Island: The Dream of America, a piece for actors and orchestra. Other notable titles by Boyer include Silver Fanfare and The Dream Lives On: A Portrait of the Kennedy Brothers.
  The website contains a biography, news, list of works, audio, video, and contact information.
- Branca, Glenn, May 2017-ongoing; cuid5882; Branca, Glenn, 1948-2018; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of glennbranca.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints. Youtube.com and seattlechannel.org domains were also included to capture two interviews with the composer.
  As of April 2025, the website contains an announcement about Branca's passing written by his wife Reg Bloor; a list of his performances; information about the Glenn Branca Ensemble; a list of his major works; and a link to the website of SYSTEMS NEUTRALIZERS, a music company run by Reg Bloor releasing her music as well as Branca's. Two interviews with Branca were also captured.
  JWPlayer video files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Glenn Branca (1948-2018) was a New York City-based composer whose works spanned a variety of genres, such as rock; large and small ensemble works for acoustic and electric instruments; opera; ballet; choral pieces; and music meant to accompany film, dance, theater, and art installations. Branca was the founder of the No Wave Movement in the 1970s and an inventor of multiple instruments including the double-body Harmonics Guitar. He also had multiple personal interests outside of the realm of music that influenced his compositions including literature, mathematics, modern philosophy, conceptual art, neo-surrealism, quantum physics, the harmonic series, and politics.
- Braxton, Tyondai, June 2018-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of tyondaibraxton.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Tyondai Braxton (b. 1978) is an American composer and electronic musician whose work incorporates modern orchestral elements in a repertoire that ranges from solo to large symphonic compositions. Examples of Braxton's recordings include the albums Telekinesis, Multiplay, Dia / Phonolydian, Oranged Out, HIVE1, and Central Market.
  The website features recent news, a list of upcoming performances, contact information, and a link to his Bandcamp page.
- Brazelton, Kitty, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5936; Brazelton, Kitty, 1951-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of kitbraz.com, listenforwhat.wordpress.com, and kitbraz.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; images associated with her music or of Brazelton herself; a discography of her published works; information about her current and past projects; a news section; a press kit; contact information; and scores of her compositions, which include embedded audio samples. Her website no longer exists at kitbraz.com, and was moved to kitbraz.info.
  Kitty Brazelton (b. 1951) is an American composer and singer based in New York. Her album releases include multiple genres, such as contemporary classical, electronic, pop, rock, punk, and avant-garde jazz. She has also fronted in bands such as Musica Orbis, Hide the Babies, the avant-garde ensemble Dadadah, and the cyberpunk trio What is it Like to Be a Bat?
- Brégégère, André, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  André Brégégère (b. 1975) is a French-born composer, educator, and visual artist based in Queens, New York. His compositions include electronic, solo, vocal, chamber, and jazz pieces. Some examples of his works are Her Story, Twelve Algorithmic Studies, Shiloh, Soliloquy No. 2, and Le temps qui passe. Brégégère is a founding member and co-director of the new music organization Dr. Faustus, as well as a new music advocate. As a scholar, he is a specialist of the music and theoretical writings of Belgian composer Henri Pousseur, who was the subject of his doctoral dissertation.
  The website contains a biography; selected music; a list of publications and presentations; and contact information. It also contains a link to his digital arts website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of abregegere.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Bresnick, Martin, May 2017-ongoing; cuid5848; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of martinbresnick.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a catalog of the artist's compositions and recordings; a biography; press features; articles; photos; a calendar of upcoming and past events; information about his concerts; his CV; and contact information.
  Martin Bresnick (b. 1946) is a contemporary composer. His works span the genres of opera, oratorio, chamber music, symphonic music, solo, vocal, film scores, and computer music. Notable works by Bresnick include the cycle Opere della Musica Povera, the oratorio Passions of Bloom, the opera My Friend's Story, the string quartet The Planet on the Table, and the piano concerto Caprichos Enfaticos, among many others. He is also a Professor of Music Composition at the Yale School of Music.
- Brett, Thomas, July 2018-ongoing; Brett, Thomas, 1971-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of brettworks.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped in an attempt to capture SoundCloud audio, as well as YouTube and Google videos.
  Thomas Brett (b. 1971) is a composer, writer, and electronic musician. He is the author of The Creative Electronic Music Producer, a book that examines the creative processes of electronic music production. He has also played mallets and percussion on Broadway since 1997.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a short biography of the artist, links to articles delving into AI in music, an archive including information about his works, information about his book The Creative Electronic Music Producer, examples of his works for film in the form of embedded video files, and other concepts of interest in music production.
- Britt, N. Cameron, April 2014-ongoing; Britt, Cameron; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ncameronbritt.com and cameronbritt.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contained a biography of the artist; blog posts on instrument building and music; and discography. In 2020, the URL changed and the page was reformatted. It mostly consists of video and SoundCloud players of his music.
  N. Cameron Britt (b. 1974) is a composer, percussionist, and instrument builder. His work combines electronic music with acoustic instruments using both hardware and software. Britt invented the EMvibe, an electromagnetically-actuated vibraphone, and is a member of the ensemble Sidebar, as well as a collaborator of PLOrk (The Princeton Laptop Orchestra).
- Brittelle, William, November 2018-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of williambrittelle.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped in an attempt to capture SoundCloud audio and Vimeo video files.
  William Brittelle (b. 1977) is a Brooklyn-based composer, producer, and creator of hyper-text and multimedia. Recent titles of albums released by Brittelle include Spiritual America, Alive in the Electric Snow Dream, and Loving the Chamber Nautilus. Brittelle is the co-founder and co-artistic director of the non-profit label New Amsterdam Records. He is also the producer for the studio Figureight Recordings; and the creator and creative director of Eternal September, a project that consists of residences, recorded music, ritual capture events, and site-specific installations composed by artists and creative technologists.
  As of April 2025, the website features a biography of the artist; contact information; high-resolution images of Brittelle; a list of selected press features; and lists of the works Brittelle has composed and produced; and projects he is involved in.
- Broderick, Peter, February 2015-ongoing; Broderick, Peter, 1987-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Peter Broderick (b. 1987) is a musician, accompanist, session player, engineer, and producer. Broderick's work includes solo compositions as well as collaborations with other artists and groups. Some of Broderick's most recent solo works include Mimi (2024), Piano Works Vol. 1 (2022), After Tunes (2022), and The Wind that Shakes The Bramble (2021).
  As of 2023, the website features announcements, a biography, contact information, a discography, links, news, and a list of shows.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of peterbroderick.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Brouwer, Margaret, February 2015- ongoing; Brouwer, Margaret, 1940-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of margaretbrouwer.com and margaret-brouwer.squarespace.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography; a calendar of her events; information and examples of her works in the form of audio and video files; a discography; and information about the projects she is involved in. It also includes reviews, interviews, press features, and photos of the artist.
  Embedded images, video, and SoundCloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Margaret Brouwer (b. 1940) is a contemporary composer and violinist of classically influenced music. Her pieces include works for chamber ensembles, orchestras, vocal, choral, solo music, and concertos. In 2011, Brouwer founded the Blue Streak Ensemble (BSE) to bring contemporary chamber music to communities of Ohio along Lake Erie. In 2015, the Margaret Brouwer Collection was established at the Library for the Performing Arts at Lincoln Center in New York City, which includes scores, manuscripts, and recordings of the artist.
- Brown, Ryan, August 2011-ongoing; Brown, Ryan, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ryanbrownmusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Ryan Brown (b. 1979) is a composer, electric guitarist, and electric bassist based in San Francisco, California. Brown's musical style is characterized by a fusion of different genres, including classical elements and modern soundscapes. His work is inspired by the visual and performing arts, and includes different types of instrumentation, ranging from orchestral symphony to electronic synthesizers.
  The website features a biography, a list of works, a list of performances, current projects, and contact information.
- Browning, Zack, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of zackbrowning.github.io and zackbrowning.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains news; listing of his compositions and recordings; reviews of his work; and information on the Salvatore Martirano Memorial Composition Award.
  Zack Browning (b. 1953) is a composer, conductor, and performer. Browning has played the trumpet with the Atlanta Symphony Orchestra and served as co-director of the Atlanta New Music Ensemble. Solo albums by Browning include Banjaxed, Soul Doctrine, Secret Pulse, and Venus Notorious.
- Bryars, Gavin, May 2017-ongoing; cuid5879; Bryars, Gavin, 1943-; 15 websites in 15 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of gavinbryars.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website no longer exists. It contained a biography of the artist; reviews of his work; a calendar of his events; image files of the artist and his performances; embedded video files recording Bryars' performances; his discography and list of works; and details about his collaborations, projects, and works in other performance media.
  Gavin Bryars (b. 1943) is an English contemporary composer and bassist. His musical compositions encompass the genres of theater, dance, chamber music, and opera. Bryars' music encompasses multiple genres including improvisation, jazz, historicism, avant-garde, experimental music, and minimalism, the latter influenced by John Cage's style. Some of Bryars' notable works include The Sinking of the Titanic (1969), Jesus' Blood Never Failed Me Yet (1971), and When Harry Met Addie (1999). Bryars has been playing with The Gavin Bryars Ensemble since 1986.
- Bunk, Lou, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of loubunk.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Lou Bunk (b. 1972) is a composer and improviser of experimental music with a background in classical composition whose work draws on avant-garde art. In his compositions, Bunk explores sound and silence through the use of microtones, amplified found objects, extended instrumental techniques, and generative approaches to texture and form. Bunk is the co-director of Collide-O-Scope Music, a New York City-based new music ensemble.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography; a list of musical compositions; audio samples; scores; a PDF of his CV; a list of upcoming events; and links to other projects by Bunk including the new music ensemble Collide-O-Scope; the concert series Opensound; the arts organization Somerville Arts Council; and the Franklin Pierce University Music Department, where he serves as Associate Professor of Music.
- Burt, Warren, February 2014- ongoing; Burt, Warren, 1949-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.warrenburt.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; a discography of his published albums; press relating to Burt and his works; downloadable versions of his scores and essays; interviews with Burt; and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files.
  Embedded PDF files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Warren Burt (1949) is an instrument maker, performer, video artist, sound poet, and composer of microtonal music who uses acoustic, electronic, and computer instruments. He makes different kinds of instruments, both in hardware and software, as well as electronic and acoustic.
- Byron, Don, May 2017; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website contained a brief biography of the artist and several of his projects; a list of his performances; a discography; information about his compositions; and excerpts of articles written about him. The site was taken down shortly after the first capture.
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of donbyron.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Don Byron (b. 1958) is a composer of music described by the artist as "a sound above genre". It utilizes a variety of instruments and styles including jazz and classical. Byron is also a multi-instrumentalist and primarily plays the clarinet. He gained notoriety as a musician and composer when he started incorporating jazz into his musical repertoire. Some of Byron's album releases include Tuskegee Experiments, Nu Blaxploitation, Bug Music, Romance with the Unseen, and A Fine Line.
- Cady, Jason, February 2015-August 2016; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of numbermadeaudible.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Jason Cady (b. 1974) is a New York City-based composer and librettist who performs on pedal steel guitar and modular synthesizer. He is the Artistic Director of Experiments in Opera, a non-profit opera company led by composers. Recent works by Cady include the operas Candy Corn, Valhalla Valley Mall, and Another One Bites. Cady's repertoire also includes sound installation, electro-acoustic, chamber, jazz, and vocal music.
  As of August 2016, the website no longer exists under this URL. It contained a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, news, and contact information.
- Cale, John, December 2009-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website contains information on the artist's latest album, tour dates, and links to his music.
  John Cale (b. 1942) is a Welsh avant-garde, rock, electronic, contemporary classical, and art music composer; record producer; and a founding member of the rock band the Velvet Underground. Cale was a member of the band from 1964-1968. In the 1970s after leaving the Velvet Underground, Cale continued his musical career as a solo artist and record producer. He produced studio albums for bands and solo artists such as The Stooges and Nico. Some of his work also includes collaborations with artists such as Lou Reed, Brian Eno, and the Talking Heads, among many others. His discography includes studio, live, and collaborative albums, as well as soundtracks and scores.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of john-cale.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Calianno, Vincent, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5852; Calianno, Vincent, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of droplid.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website includes a biography of the artist; information about L'Astronome, an opera in nine parts created with Claire Hancock; a list of his works; reels of his film and commercial musical work; a section with different types of embedded media including audio and video of his works; and contact information.
  Vincent Calianno (b. 1979) is a composer of music inspired by the American vernacular that incorporates new and obsolete technologies. Calianno's works include such genres as opera; musicals; large and small ensemble pieces; electro-acoustic music; and music for films and podcasts. Within his work as a composer for films, Calianno has created scores for early cinema productions including La Passion de Jeanne d'Arc, Das Kabinet des Dr. Caligari, and Sherlock Jr. Calianno is also a co-founder of Two Trains, a hybrid music-theatre-dance project that he created in collaboration with Claire Hancock.
- Carrick, Richard, February 2014- ongoing; Carrick, Richard, 1971-; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.richardcarrick.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; excerpts of articles and news written about Carrick and his music; a calendar of his events; a discography of his published albums; and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files.
  Embedded SoundCloud audio files and YouTube and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.